Guide to the Quentin Anderson Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence, 1937-2003
  - White, George Abbott, 1968-1971 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - White, Hayden, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Wiliams, Faith, 1969-1978 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Williams, Irene, 1972-1980 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Wolff, Cynthia, 1977-1995 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Wood, James, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Wood, Michael, 1967-1995 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Woodring, Carl, 1976-1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Woodward, C. Vann, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Zweig, Paul, 1972-1984 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- SeriesII: Writings, 1937-2001
  The second series of the collection holds Anderson's writings and notes. It has been divided into four subseries according to the original order of the materials. Many of the writings exist as drafts, as well as in final form. Notes and research undertaken in preparation for some of the writings contained in the first three subseries can be found in the fourth subseries.
  - Subseries II.1: Manuscripts and Essays, 1945-2001
    Subseries 1 is devoted to manuscripts of Anderson's books and longer essays published in a variety of journals. Materials documenting the writing and publication process of all three of his major works, The American Henry James, The Imperial Self, and Making Americans: An Essay on Individualism and Money, are found here. Also present are texts of Anderson's key essays, both in draft and final form, including materials concerning the writing and publication of "Why R.P. Blackmur Found James's Golden Bowl Inhumane," his last published work. The subject matter of these works focus mainly on American literature and its relationship to American and European culture and history, with particular attention to the life and work of 19th century American authors, Henry James, Ralph Waldo Emerson, and Walt Whitman.
    - Manuscripts
      - The American Henry James
        - Abstract and Copyright Renewal, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence, 1952-1963 (Box 14, Folder 8)
        - Henry James: Lover?, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
        - Notes on Henry James, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - Notes on The Awkward Age,undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Reception of The American Henry James, 1957-1963 (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - University Microfilms International, 1963-1995 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - The Imperial Self
        - All-Engrossing Americans, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 14)
        - Chapter III Notes--Early Version, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 15)
        - Chapter IV Notes, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 16)
        - Chapter V Notes, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 17)
        - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 18)
        - Emerson Chapter
          - 1966 (Box 14, Folder 19)
          - Early Drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
          - The Fool of Ideas, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 21)
          - Quotes, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
        - Failure of Fathers, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 2)
        - Foreword, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 3)
        - Hawthorne Chapter
          - 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 4)
          - Scarlett Letter, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 5)
          - Scarlett Letter Paradigms, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
          - Hawthorne's Boston, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
        - Knopf, 1970-1982 (Box 15, Folder 8)
        - Note Cards, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
        - Notes for Emerson, Hawthorne, James Book, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 10)
        - Permissions--Gale Research Company, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 11)
        - Preface, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
        - Public Response, 1971-1975 (Box 15, Folder 13)
        - Summary of Notes on 5x8 cards, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
        - Themes, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Making Americans: An Essay on Individualism and Money
        - Book Jacket, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 16)
        - Book Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
        - Book Notes, 1974-1992 (Box 15, Folder 18)
        - Chapter II, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 19)
        - Chapter III, 1948-1984 (Box 16, Folder 1)
        - Chapter IV, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        - Chapter V, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence--Publisher, 1978-1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
        - Creators and Acquisitors--Pound, Henry James, and Money, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 5)
        - Early Notes, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 6)
        - Essays on Money, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 7)
        - Faulkner's "Shingles for the Lord," undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
        - Interview with Quentin Anderson, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 9)
        - "Mary's Story of the Graveyard," undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
        - Melville Chapter, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 11)
        - New York Institute for the Humanities Lectures, 1982-1984 (Box 16, Folder 12)
        - Note Slips for Possible Annotations, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 13)
        - Notes on Clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 14)
        - Notes to Appear in Book, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
        - Old Chapter Divisions, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 16)
        - Permissions, 1990-1992 (Box 16, Folder 17)
        - Plans for Making Americans,undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
        - Public Reception, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 19)
        - Publisher's Party, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - Publications Copyright Information, 1976-1978 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Publications Royalties and Contracts, 1958-1999 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Essays
      - "All-Engrossing Americans," 1969 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - "American Literature and the Emergence of Modernism," 1981-1986 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence Regarding Thoreau, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - "Devouring the Hemingway Corpus," 1972 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - "Emergence of Henry James," 1975 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Essays for a Collection of Short Pieces, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - "Henry James as Allegorist," 1945-1946 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - "Henry James's Cultural Office," 1983 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - "Henry James of American City," 1952 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Henry James Revisited," 1997 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Individualism and Commerce," 1986 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - James Fenimore Cooper's "The Spy"--Graduate Seminar Paper, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - "John Dewey's American Democrat," 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - "Lionel Trilling at Columbia," 1999-2001 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - "Notes on the Personal Responsibility of the Critic," 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - "On The Middle of the Journey," undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - "The Politics of American Individualism," 1992 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - "Practical and Visionary Americans," 1976 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - "Property and Vision in 19th Century America," 1978 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - "Reconsideration: Lionel Trilling,"1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - "Speaking for Man,"1967-1969 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - "Three Points of Undivided Consciousness," undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - "Whitman's New Man," 1972 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - "Why Americans Cannot Argue," 1974 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - "Why R.P. Blackmur Found James's Golden Bowl Inhumane"
        - Blackmur's Introductions, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 14)
        - Character Study, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 15)
        - English Literary History Acceptance, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - Manuscript, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        - Peer Responses, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - Permissions, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - Research, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - Submissions, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - "Willa Cather: Her Masquerade," 1965 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Subseries II.2: Introductions and Reviews, 1949-1996
    Because of his expertise in American and British literature, Anderson was invited to write introductions for several new publications of classic literary works by American and British authors. He also periodically contributed book reviews to prominent literary publications, such as The New York Times Book Review, the Times Literary Supplement, and The New Republic. His book reviews point to Anderson's literary subject specialties--Henry James, Ralph Waldo Emerson, and Walt Whitman in particular. The text of his introductions, book reviews, and some related research are contained in this subseries.
    - Introductions
      - Bronte, Emily--Wuthering Heights,1962 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Conrad, Joseph--Lord Jim,1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Cooper, James Finemore--The Deerslayer,1961 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Eliot, George--Middlemarch,1956-1981 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Hawthorne, Nathaniel--Twice Told Tales,1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - James, Henry--Portrait of a Lady,1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - James, Henry--Selected Short Stories,1949-1977 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Melville, Herman--Moby Dick,undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Rizzuto, Anthony--Camus' Imperial Vision,undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Reviews
      - Aaron, Daniel, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Broderick, John, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Brooks, Cleanth, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Cooley, Thomas, 1976-1977 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Donald, David Herbert, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Edel, Leon, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Ellis, Joeseph, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - Fieldler, Leslie, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - Freeman, F.B., undated (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - Holland, Laurence, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Kaplan, Fred, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Kaplan, Justin, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Kermode, Frank, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Kraft, James; Shine, Muriel; Kossman, Rudolph, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - LeClair, Robert Charles, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Lewis, R.W.B., 1956, 1975, (2 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
      - Matheissen, F.O., 1949 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Nabokov, Vladimir, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Nelson, Gerald; Kaplan, Harold; Tuttleton, James, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Novak, Barbara, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Orth, Ralph and Alfred Ferguson, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Purdy, Strother, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Reynolds, David, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Shanley, Lyndon; Stern, Philip Van Doren; Anderson, Charles; Bode, Carl, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - Smith, Henry Nash, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - Thompson, Lawrance, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Turner, Arlin, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Whicher, Stephen, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Wilson, Edmund, undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Young, Fredric, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Ziff, Larzer, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Zweig, Paul, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Subseries II.3: Other Writings, 1937-1990
    Subseries 3 holds materials related to Anderson's contributions on American literary figures to encyclopedias, as well as documentation of his role as general editor and contributing author of the encyclopedia History of American Literature Series. However, the bulk of this subseries is devoted to Anderson's writings and preparations for lectures and addresses given at various academic conferences and events. Of special interest is the valedictory address that Anderson gave at the 1937 commencement ceremony, and the materials related to the lecture Anderson delivered in 1981 for the University Lecture Series at Columbia, a semi-annual event that honors the academic achievements of an exemplary faculty member.
    - Encyclopedias
      - Adventures in English Literature,1964-1966 (Box 20, Folder 25)
      - Collier's Encyclopedia,1958-1966 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Encyclopedia of American Literature,1961 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - History of American Literature Series (General Editor)
        - Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box 21, Folder 3)
        - Prospectu s and Volume Divisions, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
        - Volume I: Norman Grabo, 1964-1966 (Box 21, Folder 5)
        - Volume II: William Hedges, 1962-1971 (Box 21, Folder 6)
        - Volume III: Quentin Anderson, 1963-1965 (Box 21, Folder 7)
        - Volume IV: Carl Hovde, 1965-1972 (Box 21, Folder 8)
        - Volume V: Warner Berthoff, 1964-1966 (Box 21, Folder 9)
        - Volume VI: John McCormick, 1964-1969 (Box 21, Folder 10)
        - Volume VII: Marcus Klein, 1962-1972 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - The New Wonder World Encyclopedia,1956 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - Readers Encyclopedia of American Literature,1988 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Lectures and Addresses
      - Applied Psychoanalysis Seminar--"Whitman's New Man," 1975 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Birmingham Conference--On Literature and Society, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - British Association for American Studies--F.O. Matthiessen and the Thirties, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - Center for American Cultural Studies--"Money and the Imagination" and "Richard Poirier on the matter of America," 1988 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - Columbia College--Valedictory Address, "An Undergraduate Appraises Education," 1937 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Columbia College General Education--"The Particularity of General Education," 1979 (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - Columbia University Lecture--"American Uses of Literature," 1981 (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - The Continuing Revolutionary Tradition--"Whitman, Cultural Revolutionary," 1976 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence Concerning Lectures and Consultations, 1948-1962 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Dean's Day Lecture--"On the Dangers of Reading Great Books," 1959 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Dean's Day Lecture--"The American Imagination: The Emersonian Variety," 1964 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Fallsburgh Central High School--"Creative Writing," 1961 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Franklin and Marshall College Humanities Lecture Series--"Imagining the Powers of Money," 1982 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Henry James Society--"The Employment of Henry James," 1980 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Henry James Symposium--"The Good American," 1956 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Humanities A Course Seminar--"The Columbia College Humanities Course Past and Present," 1987 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Lifelong Learners--"Attacks on the Concept of Personal Identity," 1990 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Manchester and East Anglia Lectures--Henry James and Culture, 1963-1969 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - McGovern Speech, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Middlebury College--"John Dewey's Emersonianism," 1978 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - National Humanities Center--"Imagining the Powers of Money," 1980 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - New York Psychoanalytic Institute--Response to Dr. Jose Barchilon's "Why Ishmael, Ahab, Why Moby Dick?," 1983 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Paley Lectures in American Culture and Civilization--"The Employment of Literature in the United States" and "Henry James's American Audience," 1982 (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Phi Beta Kappa Address, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - Teacher's College--"Criticism of Modern Literature," undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - Trilling Seminar--Anderson's Introduction of Paul Ricoeur, Stanley Cavell, Clifford Geertz, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - University of Keele--"Coming Out of Culture: American Style," 1967 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Memorials
      - French, Carroll, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - Van Doren, Mark, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Subseries II.4: Notes, 1957-1997
    This subseries is comprised of research notes compiled by Anderson, presumably in preparation for many of the manuscripts, essays, reviews, and lectures contained in the three preceding subseries. A portion of the subseries is made up of index card files which Anderson used to organize his research and thoughts in preparation for his writings and teachings. Some of these notes are on individual authors and the writings of colleagues, while others serve a more general purpose such as preparatory notes for his course lectures. A significant amount of these card files are devoted to research on Henry James, including notes for Anderson's dissertation on James. The original order of these index card files has been preserved; it should be noted that Anderson's method of organizing his index cards with small, fragile tabs and dividers necessitate careful handling of the materials.
    - Adams, Henry, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - The Christian Examiner
      - General Description, undated (Box 22, Folder 24)
      - Incidence of German Thought, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Notes on Contributors, Contents, Studies, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Dana, Richard, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Dewey, John, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Dickinson, Emily, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Eliot, George
      - Comment on Manuscript by Philip Green, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Comment on Myers' on Sexual Role in Middlemarch,undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo
      - Audience: Bibliography, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Lecture Audiences: Research by Dorothy Gregory, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Manuscript for Encyclopedia Entry, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Notes for "The American Imagination: The Emersonian Strain," 1964 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Emerson and Coleridge: Russell Hartman Paper, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Emerson and William James, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Frost, Robert: Lecture Notes, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Hollis, C. Carroll: Report on "Language and Style in Leaves of Grass," undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Howe, Irving: Review of Anderson's The American Henry James,1957 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - James, Henry
      - Adam Verver, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - Chronological List of Works, undated (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Comment on Robert Durr Manuscript, undated (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - Hawthorne Introduction, 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - Notes, undated (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - James, William and Wallace Stevens Paper by Dana Brand, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Kipling, Rudyard, 1963-1965 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Moby Dick: Character of Event, undated (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Notes and Reflections, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Notes on 5x8 Cards, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Paul, Sherman: Comments on Shores of America,1971 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Pease, Donald: Comments for Darmouth, undated (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Rocqueville, Alexis de: Notes on Democracy in America,1974 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Romanticism and the American and British Subject, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Thoreau, Henry David
      - Extracts on Genealogy, Prophets, Name, undated (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - Notes on A Week on the Concord and Merrimack,1976 (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - Recent Bibliography, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Twain, Mark: Stephen Karpowitz on Twain's Psychic Symbols, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - West, Rebecca: Notes on Black Lamb,undated (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Card Files
      - Authors
        - Daniel Aaron-Ralph Waldo Emerson, undated (Box 24)
        - Erik Erikson-Norris, Frank, undated (Box 25)
        - Novak, Barbara-Zweig, Paul, undated (Box 26)
      - Literature by Subject, undated (Box 27)
      - Christian Examiner, undated (Box 27)
      - Henry James, undated (Box 28)
      - Working Notes, undated (Box 28)
      - Henry James, undated (Box 29)
      - Humanities A, undated (Box 29)
      - Colloquium on Religious Books, undated (Box 29)
      - Dissertation Notes, undated (Box 30)
- Series III: Professional Career, 1935-2002
  Series III, a record of Anderson's professional career, is divided into three subseries, remaining true to the original order of the materials. This series offers details of Anderson's career at Columbia University while a professor and illustrates his continuing involvement with the University post-retirement. It also documents his time spent as a visiting professor abroad, as well as his professional activities in academia.
  - Subseries III.1: Columbia University, 1935-2001
    Subseries 1 chronicles some particulars of Anderson's long history at Columbia University. It provides information on many of the courses Anderson taught during the 1960s and 1970s, as well as some of those that he participated in as a student. Examples of his achievements and honors while teaching can be found here, including the certificate declaring him the Julian Clarence Levi Professor Emeritus in 1981. This subseries illustrates Anderson's many involvements in university interests, such as his participation in the Columbia College Co-education Committee which recommended the admittance of women. A few items related to the 1968 campus controversy are present in this subseries.
    - 1968-1970 Controversy (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Alexander Hamilton Award Dinner, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Appointments, Promotions, Commendations, 1949-1980 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Center for American Culture Studies, 1983-1985 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Colloquium on Important Books Anniversary, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Columbia Club of New York, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Columbia College Co-education Committee, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Columbia College Core Award, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Columbia Doctorates in American Literature, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Courses
      - C 3065x, 1960-1961 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - C3273y, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - C3691x-C3692y, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 12)
        [restricted until 2056]
      - Church History Reading Lists, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - Continuing Colloquium: American Literature and Culture, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - English 19, undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - English 20: Humanities A, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - G6601x: Whitman, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
      - G6602x: Emerson, Melville, James, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 18)
      - G6631y: Post-Civil War Literature and Culture, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 19)
      - G9601x, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 20)
      - G9601x: Colloquium in American Literature and Culture, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 21)
      - Humanities C1002x, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 22)
      - Master's Exam: GSAS English, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 23)
      - Philosophy 161 and 162, 1935-1957 (Box 31, Folder 24)
      - Readings: S4603d, American Renaissance; S4644d, Henry James, undated (Box 31, Folder 25)
      - W4609x, G9601x Rosters, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 1)
        [restricted until 2057]
      - W4609 and the Committee on Instruction of the Faculty of Philosophy, 1975-1978 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Course Grade Books, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      [restricted until 2024]
    - Course Grade Books, 1947-1978 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      [restricted until 2058]
    - Course Grade Sheets: Summer Session, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      [restricted until 2062]
    - Course Proposals and Syllabus, 1970-1982 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Department of English and Comparative Literature, 1978-1986 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Dissertation Commentary
      - Henry James, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Lionel Trilling and Liberal Criticism, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Henry D. Thoreau, undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Emeritus Professors in Columbia (EPIC), 2000-2001 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Entry in Contemporary Literary Critics, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Faculty and Staff Talent Show, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Humanities A Course Guide Entry, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Humanities A 50th Anniversary, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Julian Clarence Levi Professor Emeritus, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Letters of Appointment, 1941-1984 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Public Announcements, 1961-1980 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Recruitment at Beginning Ranks, 1961-1968 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Retirement Party, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 4)